<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>DécouVerte</title>
  
  <subtitle>天下之难事必做于易，天下之大事必做于细</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://www.yluoblog.cn/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-20T03:58:50.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://www.yluoblog.cn/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Yang Luo</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How To Writing Academic Essay  | 学术论文写作总结</title>
    <link href="http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/18/How-To-Writing-Academic-Essay/"/>
    <id>http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/18/How-To-Writing-Academic-Essay/</id>
    <published>2017-10-18T07:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-20T03:58:50.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="写在前面"><a href="#写在前面" class="headerlink" title="写在前面"></a>写在前面</h1><p>最近正在写学术论文，无意间拜读到了一篇国外大牛的文章，里面详细的讲解了如何去组织、撰写一篇学术论文。我把这个文章原文放在这里，也加入了一些自己的理解，希望对看到这篇博客的人能有所帮助吧。。。</p><h1 id="Writing-Introductions"><a href="#Writing-Introductions" class="headerlink" title="Writing Introductions"></a>Writing Introductions</h1><p>There are many ways to introduce an academic essay or assignment. Most academic writers, however, appear to do one or more of the following in their introductions:</p><ul><li>establish the context, background and/or importance of the topic</li><li>indicate a problem, controversy or a gap in the field of study</li><li>define the topic or key terms</li><li>state of the purpose of the essay/writing</li><li>provide an overview of the coverage and/or structure of the writing </li></ul><blockquote><p>Introduction的结构：背景，问题，目的，结构</p></blockquote><p>Examples of phrases which are commonly employed to realise these functions are listed below. Note that there may be a certain amount of overlap between some of the categories under which the phrases are listed.</p><p>Introductory sections for research dissertations, are normally much more complex than this and, as well as the elements above, may include the following: <code>a synopsis of key literature/current state of knowledge</code>, <code>synopsis of methods</code> ,<code>lists of research questions or hypotheses to be tested</code>, <code>significance of the study</code>, <code>recognition of the limitations of the study, reasons for personal interest in the topic</code>.</p><h2 id="Establishing-the-importance-of-the-topic"><a href="#Establishing-the-importance-of-the-topic" class="headerlink" title="Establishing the importance of the topic"></a>Establishing the importance of the topic</h2><p><code>One of the most significant current discussions</code> in legal and moral philososphy is ……<br>It is <code>becoming increasingly difficult</code> to ignore the …..<br><code>X is the leading cause of</code> death in western industrialised countries.<br>X is a common disorder characterised by ……<br><code>X is an important component in</code> the climate system, and <code>plays a key role</code> in Y.<br>In the new global economy, X has <code>become a central issue</code> for ……<br>In the history of development economics, X has <code>been thought of as a key factor</code> in …….<br>Xs are one of the most widely used groups of antibacterial agents and ……<br>Xs are the most potent anti-infammatory agents known.</p><p>Recent developments in X have <code>heightened the need for</code> ……<br>In recent years, there has been an increasing interest in ……<br><code>Recent developments in the field of X</code> have led to a <code>renewed interest</code> in ……<br>Recently, researchers have shown an increased interest in ……<br>The past decade has seen <code>the rapid development</code> of X in many …….<br>The past thirty years have seen <code>increasingly rapid advances in the field of</code>……<br>Over the past century there has been <code>a dramatic increase</code> in ……<br>One of the most important events of the 1970s was ……<br>Traditionally, Xs have subscribed to the belief that ……<br>X proved an important literary genre in the early Y community.<br><code>The changes experienced by Xs</code> over the past decade <code>remain unprecedented</code>.<br>Xs are one of the most widely used groups of antibacterial agents and have been <code>extensively used</code> for decades to ……. </p><h2 id="Highlighting-a-problem-or-controversy-in-the-field-of-study"><a href="#Highlighting-a-problem-or-controversy-in-the-field-of-study" class="headerlink" title="Highlighting a problem or controversy in the field of study"></a>Highlighting a problem or controversy in the field of study</h2><blockquote><p>研究领域有争议，有问题的写法</p></blockquote><p>However, these rapid changes are having <code>a serious effect</code> ……<br>However, <code>a major problem</code> with this kind of application is ……<br>To date <code>there has been little agreement on</code> what ……<br>More recently, literature has emerged that offers <code>contradictory findings</code> about …..<br>There is increasing concern that some Xs are being disadvantaged ……<br>Despite its long clinical success, X has <code>a number of problems in use</code>.<br>Despite its safety and efficacy, X suffers from several major drawbacks:<br><code>Concerns have been raised by</code> several relevant bodies about the poor ……<br>One of <code>the most significant current discussions</code> in legal and moral philososphy is ……<br>One observer has already <code>drawn attention to</code> the paradox in ……<br>In many Xs <code>a debate is taking place between Ys and Zs</code> concerning ……<br>The controversy about scientific evidence for X <code>has raged unabated for over a century</code>.<br>The issue of X has been <code>a controversial and much disputed subject</code> within the field of …….<br>The issue has grown in importance<code>in light of</code> recent ……<br>One major theoretical issue that has <code>dominated the field</code> for many years concerns ……<br>One major issue in <code>early X research</code> concerned…….</p><blockquote><p>研究领域有问题被忽视</p></blockquote><p>So far, however, <code>there has been little discussion about</code> ……<br>However, <code>far too little attention has been paid to</code> ……<br>Most studies in X have only been <code>carried out in a small number of areas</code>.<br>The research to date has tended to <code>focus on X rather than Y</code>.<br>In addition, no research has been found that surveyed …….<br>So far this method has <code>only been applied to</code> ……<br>Several studies have produced estimates of X (Smith, 2002; Jones, 2003), but <code>there is still insufficient data for</code> …..<br>However, there have been no controlled studies <code>which compare differences in</code>……<br>The experimental data are<code>rather controversial</code>, and <code>there is no general agreement about</code> ……</p><h2 id="Focus-and-aim"><a href="#Focus-and-aim" class="headerlink" title="Focus and aim"></a>Focus and aim</h2><p>This paper will <code>focus on</code>/<code>examine</code>/<code>give</code> an account of ……<br>This paper <code>seeks to</code> address the following questions: …..<br>This essay critically <code>examines</code>/<code>discusses</code>/<code>traces</code> ……<br>The purpose of this paper is to review recent research into the ……<br>This paper will review the research <code>conducted on</code> ……<br>In this paper I argue that …..<br>This chapter reviews the literature concerning the usefulness of using ……<br>The aim of this paper is to <code>determine</code>/examine ……<br>The aim of this study was to <code>evaluate</code> and <code>validate</code> …… </p><h2 id="Outline-of-structure"><a href="#Outline-of-structure" class="headerlink" title="Outline of structure"></a>Outline of structure</h2><p>The main questions/issues addressed in this paper are: a), b and c).<br>This paper has <code>been divided into</code> four parts. The first part deals with ……<br>The essay has been organised in the following way.<br>This paper first gives a brief overview of the recent history of X.<br>This paper begins by …… It will then go on to ……<br>The first section of this paper will examine ……<br>Finally, …….<br>Chapter 2 begins by laying out the theoretical dimensions of the research, and looks at how ……<br>Chapter 3 describes the design, synthesis, characterization and evaluation of ……<br>The last chapter <code>assesses</code> the ……</p><h2 id="Explaining-Keywords"><a href="#Explaining-Keywords" class="headerlink" title="Explaining Keywords"></a>Explaining Keywords</h2><p>While a variety of definitions of the term X have been suggested, this paper will use the definition first suggested by Smith (1968) who saw it as …….<br>Throughout this paper the term X will refer to/will be used to refer to …….<br>In this article the acronym/abbreviation XYZ will be used. </p><h2 id="Being-Critical"><a href="#Being-Critical" class="headerlink" title="Being Critical"></a>Being Critical</h2><p>As an academic writer, you are expected to be critical of the sources that you use. This essentially means questioning what you read and not necessarily agreeing with it just because the information has been published. Being critical can also mean looking for reasons why we should not just accept something as being correct or true. This can require you to identify problems with a writer’s arguments or methods, or perhaps to refer to other people’s criticisms of these. Constructive criticism goes beyond this by suggesting ways in which a piece of research or writing could be improved.<br><em>…..being against is not enough. We also need to develop habits of constructive thinking. Edward de Bono</em></p><h2 id="Introducing-questions-problems-and-limitations"><a href="#Introducing-questions-problems-and-limitations" class="headerlink" title="Introducing questions, problems and limitations"></a>Introducing questions, problems and limitations</h2><h3 id="theory"><a href="#theory" class="headerlink" title="theory"></a>theory</h3><p>One question that needs to be asked, however, is whether ……<br>A serious weakness with this argument, however, is that ……<br>One of the <code>limitations</code> with this explanation is that it does not explain why …..<br>One criticism of much of the literature on X is that ……<br>The key problem with this explanation is that ……<br>The existing accounts fail to resolve the contradiction between X and Y.<br>However, there is an inconsistency with this argument.<br>Smith’s argument <code>relies too heavily</code> on qualitative analysis of ……<br>It seems that Jones’ understanding of the X framework is <code>questionable</code>.<br>Smith’s interpretation overlooks much of the historical research ……<br>One major criticism of Smith’s work is that …..<br>Many writers have <code>challenged Jones&#39; claim on the grounds</code> that …….</p><h3 id="method-practice"><a href="#method-practice" class="headerlink" title="method/practice"></a>method/practice</h3><p>Another problem with this approach is that it fails to<code>take X into account</code>.<br>Perhaps the most serious disadvantage of this method is that …..<br>Difficulties <code>arise</code>, however, when an attempt is made to implement the policy.<br>Nevertheless, the strategy has not escaped criticism from governments, agencies and academics.<br>One major drawback of this approach is that ……<br>The main limitation of biosynthetic incorporation, however, is ……<br>However, this method of analysis has a number of limitations.<br>However, approaches of this kind carry with them various well known limitations.<br>All the studies reviewed so far, however, <code>suffer from</code> the fact that …<br>However, all the previously mentioned methods suffer from some serious <code>limitations</code>/<code>weaknesses</code>/<code>disadvantages</code>/<code>drawbacks</code>.</p><h2 id="Identifying-a-study’s-weakness"><a href="#Identifying-a-study’s-weakness" class="headerlink" title="Identifying a study’s weakness"></a>Identifying a study’s weakness</h2><p>the main weakness of the study <code>is the failure to</code> address how …….<br>the study <code>fails to</code> consider the differing categories of damage that …..<br>the research does not take into account pre-existing …… such as ……<br>the author offers no explanation for the distinction between X and Y.<br>Smith makes no attempt to differentiate between various different types of X.<br>Jones fails to fully acknowledge the significance of ……<br>the paper would appear to be over ambitious in its claims<br>the author overlooks the fact that X contributes to Y.<br>what Smith fails to do is to <code>draw a distinction between</code> ……<br>another weakness is that we are given no explanantion of how ……</p><h2 id="Offering-constructive-suggestions"><a href="#Offering-constructive-suggestions" class="headerlink" title="Offering constructive suggestions"></a>Offering constructive suggestions</h2><p><code>Smith&#39;s paper/Her conclusions/The study/The findings</code>   <code>would/might</code> have been <code>more/much more/far more</code>   <code>useful/convincing/interesting/persuasive/original</code> if <code>he/she/author</code> had <code>included/considered/adopted/used</code>…..</p><p>A better study would examine a large, randomly selected sample of societies with ……<br>A much more systematic study would identify how X <code>interacts with</code> other variables that are believed to be linked to ……</p><h2 id="Introducing-other-people’s-criticisms"><a href="#Introducing-other-people’s-criticisms" class="headerlink" title="Introducing other people’s criticisms"></a>Introducing other people’s criticisms</h2><p>However, Jones (2003) <code>points out</code> that …..<br>Many analysts now argue that the strategy of X has not been successful. Jones (2003), for example, argues that …..<br>Non-government agencies are also very critical of the new policies.<br>The X theory has been <code>vigorously</code> / <code>strongly</code> challenged in recent years by a number of writers.<br>Smith’s analysis has been criticised by a number of writers. Jones (1993), for example, points out that ……<br>Smith’s meta-analysis has <code>been subjected to</code> considerable criticism.<br>The most important of these criticisms is that Smith failed to note that ……<br>Jones (2003) is probably the best known critic of the X theory. He argues that .….<br>The latter point has been devastatingly critiqued by Jones (2003).<br>Critics have also argued that not only do social surveys provide an inaccurate measure of X, but the……<br>Critics question the ability of poststructuralist theory to provide ……<br>More recent arguments against X have been summarised by Smith and Jones (1982):<br>Jones (2003) is critical of the conclusions that Smith draws from his findings. </p><h1 id="Reporting-Results"><a href="#Reporting-Results" class="headerlink" title="Reporting Results"></a>Reporting Results</h1><p>The standrard approach is to this section of dissertations is to <code>merely</code> present the results, without elaborate discussion or comment. This does not mean that you do not need any text to describe data presented in tables and figures. Writers usually comment on the significant data presented in the tables and figures. This often takes the form of the location or summary statement, which identifies the table or figure and indicates its content. This may be followed by a statement or statements which point out and describe the relevant or significant data. All your tables should be numbered and given a title.</p><p>More elaborate commentary on the results is normally restricted to the <strong>Discussion section</strong>. In research articles, however, authors may comment extensively on their results as they are presented, and it is not uncommon for the Results section to be combined with the Discussion section under the heading: Results and Discussion. </p><h2 id="Reference-to-aim-method"><a href="#Reference-to-aim-method" class="headerlink" title="Reference to aim/method"></a>Reference to aim/method</h2><p>To assess X, the Y questionnaire was used.<br>To distinguish between these two possibilities, ……<br>In order to assess Z, repeated measures of ANOVA were used.<br>Regression analysis was used to predict the ……<br>Changes in X and Y were compared using ……<br>The average scores of X and Y were compared in order to ……<br>Nine items on the questionnaire measured the extent to which ……<br>The correlation between X and Y was tested.<br>The first set of analyses examined the impact of ……<br>Simple statistical analysis was used to ……<br>A scatter diagram and a Pearson’s product moment correlation were used to determine the relationship between ……<br>T-tests were used to analyse the relationship between ……</p><blockquote><p>学术论文中一般对方法的描述都是被动语态，例如 be used to…..</p></blockquote><h2 id="Location-and-summary-statements"><a href="#Location-and-summary-statements" class="headerlink" title="Location and summary statements"></a>Location and summary statements</h2><p><code>Table 1/Figure 1</code> <code>shows/compares/presents/provides</code> <code>the experimental data on X/the results obtained from the preliminary analysis of X/the intercorrelations among the nine measures of X</code>. </p><p>The results obtained from the preliminary analysis of X <code>are shown/can becompared/are presented</code> in <code>Table 1/Figure 1</code>. </p><p><code>As shown in Figure 12.1/As canbe seen from the table (above)/It canbe seen from the data in Table 12.1 that/From the graph above we can see that</code>  the X group reported significantly more Y than the other two groups. </p><p><code>The table below illustrates/The pie chart above shows</code> <code>some of the main characteristics of the...../the breakdown of.....</code></p><h2 id="Highlighting-significant-data-in-a-table-chart"><a href="#Highlighting-significant-data-in-a-table-chart" class="headerlink" title="Highlighting significant data in a table/chart"></a>Highlighting significant data in a table/chart</h2><p>It is apparent from this table that very few ……<br>This table <code>is quite revealing in several ways</code>. First, unlike the other tables ……<br>Data from this table can<code>be compared with</code> the data in Table 4.6 which shows ……<br>From the data in Figure 9, it is apparent that the length of time left between ……<br>From this data we can see that Study 2 <code>resulted in</code> the lowest value of ……<br>The histogram in Fig 1. indicates that ……<br>What is interesting in this data is that ……<br>In Fig.10 there is a clear trend of decreasing ……<br>As Table III shows, there is <code>a significant difference</code> (t = -2.15, p = 0.03) between the two groups.</p><h2 id="Statements-of-result"><a href="#Statements-of-result" class="headerlink" title="Statements of result"></a>Statements of result</h2><h3 id="positive"><a href="#positive" class="headerlink" title="positive"></a>positive</h3><p>Strong evidence of X was found when ……<br>This result is significant at the p = 0.05 level.<br>There was a significant positive correlation between ……<br>There was a signifcant difference between the two conditions ……<br>On average, Xs were shown to have ……<br>The mean score for X was ……<br>Interestingly, for those subjects with X, ……<br>A positive correlation was found between X and Y.</p><p>Further analysis showed that ……<br>Further statistical tests revealed …..</p><h3 id="negative"><a href="#negative" class="headerlink" title="negative"></a>negative</h3><p>There was no increase of X associated with …..<br>There were no significant differences between ……<br>No significant differences were found between …..<br>No increase in X was detected.<br>No difference greater than X was observed.<br>The Chi-square test did not show any significant differences between ……<br>None of these differences were statistically significant.<br>Overall, X did not affect males and females differently in these measure</p><h2 id="Highlighting-significant-interesting-or-surprising-results"><a href="#Highlighting-significant-interesting-or-surprising-results" class="headerlink" title="Highlighting significant, interesting or surprising results"></a>Highlighting significant, interesting or surprising results</h2><p>The most striking result to emerge from the data is that ……<br>Interestingly, this correlation is related to …..<br>The correlation between X and Y is interesting because ……<br>The more surprising correlation is with the ……<br>The single most striking observation to emerge from the data comparison was ……</p><h2 id="Reporting-results-from-questionnaires-and-interviews"><a href="#Reporting-results-from-questionnaires-and-interviews" class="headerlink" title="Reporting results from questionnaires and interviews"></a>Reporting results from questionnaires and interviews</h2><p>The response rate was 60% at six months and 56% at 12 months.<br>Of the study population, 90 subjects completed and returned the questionnaire.<br>Of the initial cohort of 123 students, 66 were female and 57 male.<br>The majority of respondents/those who responded felt that …..<br>Over half of those surveyed reported that ……<br>70% of those who were interviewed indicated that ……<br>Almost two-thirds of the participants (64%) said that ……<br>Approximately half of those surveyed did not comment on ……<br>A small number of those interviewed suggested that ……<br>Only a small number of respondents indicated that ……<br>Of the 148 patients who completed the questionnaire, just over half indicated that …….<br>A minority of participants (17%) indicated ……<br>In response to Question 1, most of those surveyed indicated that ……<br>The overall response to this question was very positive.<br>When the subject were asked ……, the majority commented that …..<br>Other responses to this question included ……<br>The overall response to this question was poor.</p><h2 id="Transition-statements"><a href="#Transition-statements" class="headerlink" title="Transition statements"></a>Transition statements</h2><p>Turning now to the experimental evidence on ……<br>Comparing the two results, it can be seen that ……<br>A comparison of the two results reveals ……<br>If we now turn to ……</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#写在前面&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;写在前面&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;最近正在写学术论文，无意间拜读到了一篇国外大牛的文章，里面详细的讲解了如何去组织、撰写一篇学术论文。我把这个文章原文放在这里
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="summary" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/summary/"/>
    
      <category term="scholarism" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/scholarism/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How To Writing Academic Essay  | 学术论文词汇总结</title>
    <link href="http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/18/%E5%AD%A6%E6%9C%AF%E8%AE%BA%E6%96%87%E8%AF%8D%E6%B1%87%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/"/>
    <id>http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/18/学术论文词汇总结/</id>
    <published>2017-10-18T07:57:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-20T12:25:06.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="介词"><a href="#介词" class="headerlink" title="介词"></a>介词</h1><h2 id="转折关系"><a href="#转折关系" class="headerlink" title="转折关系"></a>转折关系</h2><ul><li>然而           <code>However</code>; <code>Nevertheless</code></li><li>尽管           <code>Despite</code>; </li></ul><h2 id="递进关系"><a href="#递进关系" class="headerlink" title="递进关系"></a>递进关系</h2><ul><li>更进一步地  <code>Moreover</code>; <code>Furthermore</code>; <code>In addition</code>; </li><li>尤其地          <code>Particularly</code>;</li><li>同时           <code>whilst</code>; </li></ul><h2 id="因果关系"><a href="#因果关系" class="headerlink" title="因果关系"></a>因果关系</h2><ul><li>因此            <code>Consequently</code>; <code>Therefore</code></li><li>由于           <code>Due to</code></li></ul><h2 id="过渡与总结"><a href="#过渡与总结" class="headerlink" title="过渡与总结"></a>过渡与总结</h2><ul><li>到目前为止   <code>By now</code>; <code>To date</code>; <code>More recently</code>; <code>as-of-yet</code>; <code>So far</code>;</li><li>大体上来说   <code>by and large</code>; </li></ul><h1 id="短语"><a href="#短语" class="headerlink" title="短语"></a>短语</h1><ul><li>展示、呈现   <code>be present</code>; <code>be depicted</code>;<code>be described</code>; <code>be displayed</code> ; <code>indicate that...</code> ; </li><li>利用               <code>use</code>; <code>leverage</code>; </li><li>缺点、劣势   <code>disadvantages</code>; <code>drawbacks</code>; </li><li>关注              <code>drawn attention to</code>; <code>concerning</code>; <code>concern about</code>; <code>conducted on</code>; </li><li>根据、依据   <code>according to</code>; <code>in light of</code>; </li><li>广泛使用      <code>extensively used</code>; <code>widely used</code></li><li>被简化为      <code>be abbreviated to</code>; </li><li>上述的、上面提及的 <code>abovementioned</code>; <code>aforementioned</code>;</li><li>期望的          <code>desired</code>; <code>expected</code>; </li><li>描绘、关注…问题   <code>focus on</code>; <code>examine</code>; <code>discuss</code>; <code>trace</code>; <code>take ... into account</code>; </li><li>忽视              <code>overlook</code>; <code>ignore</code>;</li><li>意义、重要性 <code>significance</code>; </li><li>有意义的，相关的 <code>relevant</code>; <code>significant</code>;</li><li>强烈地 <code>vigorously</code>; <code>strongly</code></li><li>遭受 <code>be subjected to</code>; <code>suffer from</code></li><li>仅仅 <code>merely</code>; <code>barely</code>; </li><li>详尽的 <code>elaborate</code>;</li></ul><p>accommodate 适应 </p><p>denote 表示</p><p>proof-of-concept 概念验证</p><p>has raged unabated for over a century 持续了一个多世纪</p><p>via 通过 </p><p>adhere to 坚持、追随、秉承</p><p>in either/this scenario 在 其他/这种 情景</p><p>heuristically 启发式地、试探性地</p><p>an account of 一份…的说明</p><p>recent research 最近的研究</p><p>limitations 局限性</p><p>rely too heavily on…. 过于依赖</p><p>questionable 可疑的，有问题的</p><p>challenged Jones’ claim on the grounds 对Jone的主张提出质疑</p><p>pre-existing 先已存在的</p><p>systematic study 系统研究</p><p>interacts with 相互作用</p><p>point out 指出</p><p>assess 评估、评价</p><h1 id="专业词汇"><a href="#专业词汇" class="headerlink" title="专业词汇"></a>专业词汇</h1><p>three-phase dc-brushless motor  三相直流无刷电机</p><p>resolver 旋转变压器</p><p>three-bladed nylon propeller 三叶的尼龙桨</p><p>pulsewidth-modulated (PWM) 脉宽调制</p><p>4096 counts per revolution 每转4096线</p><p>revolution 转速</p><p>advance speed 推进速度、前进速度</p><p>four quadrant nonlinear function 四象限非线性方程</p><p>wake fraction number 伴流系数(0.1~0.4)</p><p>affine thruster model 仿射的推进器模型</p><p>lump parameter of various constants 集中参数</p><p>cavitation 空化现象</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;介词&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#介词&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;介词&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;介词&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;转折关系&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#转折关系&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;转折关系&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;转折关系&lt;/h
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="summary" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/summary/"/>
    
      <category term="scholarism" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/scholarism/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo+Github Pages搭建个人博客</title>
    <link href="http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/17/Hexo+Github%20Pages%E6%90%AD%E5%BB%BA%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/"/>
    <id>http://www.yluoblog.cn/2017/10/17/Hexo+Github Pages搭建个人博客/</id>
    <published>2017-10-17T12:32:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-24T02:43:36.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="写在前面"><a href="#写在前面" class="headerlink" title="写在前面"></a>写在前面</h1><p>折腾了整整一周，终于搭建好了我的个人博客。感谢互联网的发达让信息共享如此方便，让我仅仅用了不到三天就弄好了自己的独立博客。在这篇博客的最后我也会列出非常值得参考的几篇博客教程与网站供大家学习。</p><h1 id="准备工作"><a href="#准备工作" class="headerlink" title="准备工作"></a>准备工作</h1><p>在打造个人博客之前，需要进行以下准备工作：</p><ul><li><strong><a href="www.github.com">Github</a>账号注册</strong>  这是为了在Github上部署你的博客，相当于申请了一个服务器，空间免费。</li><li><strong><a href="https://www.qiniu.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">七牛</a>账号注册</strong> 由于Github上的免费空间有限，一些大图片保存在Github上会占用空间，七牛上提供免费的10G空间，可以存储一些图片视频之类文件。</li><li><strong>申请一个域名</strong>  有了独立域名，逼格才能满满~我是在腾讯云申请的域名，一年10多块钱。</li></ul><p>有了这些，就可以开始打造自己的独立博客了，那么首先我们在电脑上安装一些软件。</p><h1 id="软件安装"><a href="#软件安装" class="headerlink" title="软件安装"></a>软件安装</h1><p>我是在Windows下使用Github的，所以需要安装以下软件：</p><ul><li><strong><a href="https://nodejs.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="external">Node.js</a></strong> 一个基于 Chrome V8 引擎的JavaScript 运行时</li><li><strong><a href="https://git-scm.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Git</a></strong> 用来部署Git</li></ul><p>有了这两个软件，其实就已经可以开始接下来的部署Hexo了。不过由于Hexo是用Markdown语言来写博客的，为了方便起见，我推荐一个Markdown的编辑器：</p><ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.typora.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Typora</a></strong> 超级好用，界面还美观</li><li><strong><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Visual Studio Code</a></strong> 微软推出的代码编辑器，因为配置Hexo时候需要修改一些xml文件，感觉这个编辑器挺好用的</li></ul><p>好啦，软件安装完毕，那么我们就开始配置域名吧~</p><h1 id="域名配置"><a href="#域名配置" class="headerlink" title="域名配置"></a>域名配置</h1><p>域名申请完之后要设置域名解析，设置如下：</p><ul><li>域名的DNS要设置为：f1g1ns1.dnspod.net 和 f1g1ns2.dnspod.net</li></ul><div class="table-container"><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center">主机记录</th><th style="text-align:center">记录类型</th><th style="text-align:center">记录值</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">@</td><td style="text-align:center">A</td><td style="text-align:center">192.30.252.153</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">@</td><td style="text-align:center">A</td><td style="text-align:center">192.30.252.154</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">www</td><td style="text-align:center">CNAME</td><td style="text-align:center">githubname.github.io</td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>其中githubname为自己的github账号名称，这样你自己申请域名就能够解析到你的Github Pages上了。</p><h1 id="配置Github"><a href="#配置Github" class="headerlink" title="配置Github"></a>配置Github</h1><p>我们要配置SSH keys将本地的Git项目与远程Github建立联系</p><ul><li>检查电脑上现有的SSH keys:<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ cd ~/. ssh 检查本机SSH keys</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><p>如果提示：No such file or directory 说明为第一次使用Git</p><ul><li>生成新的SSH key：<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ ssh-keygen -t rsa -C &quot;邮件地址@youremail.com&quot;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><p>之后回车，然后输密码，以后提交项目的时候就输入这个密码。</p><ul><li><p>将本机的SSH key添加到Github上，在id_rsa.pub文件中。登陆Github-&gt;Accout Settings-&gt;SSH Public keys-&gt;add another public keys，把文件中的密钥粘贴到里面，点击add key。</p></li><li><p>测试一下，输入以下命令</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ ssh -T git@github.com</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li><li><p>设置用户信息：</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ git config --global user.name &quot;cnfeat&quot;//用户名</div><div class="line">$ git config --global user.email  &quot;cnfeat@gmail.com&quot;//填写自己的邮箱</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li><li><p>在Github上创建一个新仓库，名字后缀固定，比如我的Github账号为thinkexist1989，那么仓库的名字就要设置为thinkexist1989.github.io.</p></li></ul><h1 id="搭建Hexo框架"><a href="#搭建Hexo框架" class="headerlink" title="搭建Hexo框架"></a>搭建Hexo框架</h1><p>Hexo是一个简单、快速、强大的博客发布工具，支持Markdown格式。</p><h2 id="安装Hexo"><a href="#安装Hexo" class="headerlink" title="安装Hexo"></a>安装Hexo</h2><p>打开Git Bash</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ npm install -g hexo</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="部署Hexo"><a href="#部署Hexo" class="headerlink" title="部署Hexo"></a>部署Hexo</h2><p>新建一个文件夹，然后在这个文件夹中运行Git Bash</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo init</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Hexo随后会在这个文件夹下生成网站所需要的所有文件，之后可以本地部署并查看生成的网页<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo g</div><div class="line">$ hexo s -p 5000</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>然后在浏览器输入localhost:5000便可以查看网页了(因为我安了福昕PDF，占用了4000端口)，<strong>建议使用Chrome浏览器</strong></p><h1 id="安装NeXT主题"><a href="#安装NeXT主题" class="headerlink" title="安装NeXT主题"></a>安装NeXT主题</h1><p>参考中的[NeXT主题官方网站][NeXT主题官方网站]中有更加详细的安装与配置说明，在这里只简单介绍一下安装步骤：</p><h2 id="下载主题"><a href="#下载主题" class="headerlink" title="下载主题"></a>下载主题</h2><p>在Hexo文件夹下运行Git Bash：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ git clone https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next themes/next</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h2 id="启用主题"><a href="#启用主题" class="headerlink" title="启用主题"></a>启用主题</h2><p>打开Hexo根目录下的_config.xml文件，找到<code>theme</code>字段，将其值改成<code>next</code></p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">theme:next</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>这样便配置好了NeXT主题，NeXT具有丰富的功能与样式配置，具体的可以参考[NeXT主题官方网站][NeXT主题官方网站]</p><h1 id="发布博客"><a href="#发布博客" class="headerlink" title="发布博客"></a>发布博客</h1><p>博客需要用Markdown语言编写，写好之后，将博客放到source-&gt;_post文件夹下，这里就是存放所有博客文件的地方，之后执行如下命令：<br><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">$ hexo clean</div><div class="line">$ hexo g -d</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>执行完上述语句之后，GIthub上便已经部署好了，但是还有一个重要的步骤：登陆Github，进入博客的仓库，新建一个文件，重命名为CNAME，内容填写为你自己的域名，比如www.yluoblog.cn。之后保存。这样在网页中输入自己的域名，才能够解析到Github Pages。</p><h1 id="写在后面"><a href="#写在后面" class="headerlink" title="写在后面"></a>写在后面</h1><p>从无到有，经过自己的一顿折腾，在网页中输入自己的域名可以登录到博客的那一刻，心情真的是很激动！我之后也会将我所学到一些东西在博客中分享出来！学习是一个快乐的过程，希望每个人都能从学习中找到属于自己的快乐！</p><h1 id="参考"><a href="#参考" class="headerlink" title="参考"></a>参考</h1><ol><li><a href="http://blog.csdn.net/poem_of_sunshine/article/details/29369785/" target="_blank" rel="external">如何搭建一个独立博客——简明Github Pages与Hexo教程</a></li><li><a href="http://www.chinaz.com/web/2016/0105/491998.shtml" target="_blank" rel="external">如何使用10个小时搭建出个人域名而又Geek的独立博客？</a></li><li><a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo官方网站</a></li><li><a href="http://theme-next.iissnan.com/getting-started.html" target="_blank" rel="external">NeXT主题官方网站</a></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#写在前面&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;写在前面&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;写在前面&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;折腾了整整一周，终于搭建好了我的个人博客。感谢互联网的发达让信息共享如此方便，让我仅仅用了不到三天就弄好了自己的独立博客。在
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="tutorials" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/tutorials/"/>
    
      <category term="practise" scheme="http://www.yluoblog.cn/tags/practise/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
